The origin of my vascular system, the periphery, is also strongly
integrated into the yolk sac.
At the same time, I have my amniotic cavity.
I have this amniotic cavity that is as large at first as my yolk sac.
The embryo will grow enormously, will elongate.
And here we see, look at how the importance of this cavity comes to integrate my
yolk sac system.
You see, it comes completely to wrap around.
And that's the movement.
that I want us to work on today.
It is in this movement that, you see, this whole yolk sac system
resorbs towards the center of the embryo, you see.
It's all this movement that it reintegrates.
And so, it is this amniotic cavity, this zone B, as I call it,
in relation to my aortic system, that breathes everything back to the center,
both on an abdominal and thoracic transversal plane.
Little by little, the growth.
The establishment of the heart with the enormous growth of the brain, the
movement this time of my amniotic cavity, you see, which completely takes
everything.
It will occupy all the space of what we call the external coelom.
There is only part of this internal coelom that will be integrated into one internal coelom.
You see, this amniotic cavity, in fact, it will stop, but we will see that it will still grow, grow, grow.
And you see, the more it grows, the more this integrates.
Look again here.
This is the summary on two slides of the entire integration
of your arterial system,
that is to say, the integration of your arterial system from the periphery to the center,
that is to say, cephalization leading to cardiacization,
leading to diaphragmization, hepatization, and so it's all the enlistment.
So the head is here and there I have my amniotic cavity and the amniotic cavity
does what? Look at the drawing, you come back to my hand.
Look at the drawing, you come back to my hand, it will completely integrate all
this so it will redefine, and in this phase, both like this and
like this I have the construction of my zone B and so it’s as if the yolk
sac, which contained the primitive information on the venous plane does this
at the same time that I have the outside doing this.
And the combination of the two reintegrates my venous system inside.
The secret is to bring the fluids back to the center,
that is the fascial system which is predominant for release.
Third thing, is that my yolk sac contains a great source of information
and that is the movement of integration of both the external coelom into an internal coelom.
Closure of the neural tube and all the integration and all the movement that comes to reintegrate
towards the center and all the construction here that is provided by my cavity.
So what we are going to do is give back this cavity, give back this zone B to
reintegrate your circulation inside.
Here I have prepared the slide as if I had a person lying here, reclining.
The diagram just needs to be flipped in relation to the film.
In blue here.
This will be the integration into a neural tube and the rest will form the skin
here, you see, which is an ectoderm layer.
Then, at the same time as I have this movement, I have the integration of my yolk
sac to form a part that we will call the digestive system.
But at the same time, I have the entire integration of my venous system.
The movement to follow for us is a movement that develops around with
my amniotic cavity.
Here, as it grows, and then at some point there is a fusion that will happen to form the
longitudinal part of the digestive tube and here the integration I have drawn in yellow
here
to show the integration of the external coelom into a future internal coelom where this will meet
on the midline like this, so I have both the big motor for all this is my
notochordal system which influences my tube
that is my
primitive aortic vascular system which redirects all
the information with
the gradual integration of this whole transversal system from the periphery
to the center
and so all this movement I visualize this and I have this and
what we are going to do is
follow this movement more and more, exaggerate it, just
put the hands and let it happen
the primary breathing I will guide you
At the same time, it will be a reintegration of your vascular system and at the same time,
it will be the protection of your zone B, if you will, amniotic cavity,
which is still there, but in another form.
So, the devitalizing movement of the lungs starts from the endoderm, and actually, it will make a movement
like this.
But it's still directed by the vascular system too, huh, don't forget.
So, in fact, the awareness...
of the umbilical stalk must return
into this space here. Because it’s
like this that you see that
I have the force of the amniotic cavity
that grows,
but that at the same time has the process
of cephalization, cardiacization,
hepatization, and then
I have all the return like this. And it is there that
my yolk sac, pushed by
the speed of differential growth
at the lower part
compared to my allantois,
which will be picked up in the diagram and comes to push the stalk that is
here
to join my yolk sac to later form the umbilical cord.
Everything will meet here.
We start in a certain way on its stalk and we return to a cord.